# Sindhura Mudduluri

# **QA Test Engineer - HSBC**

McLean, VA sindhuramqa@gmail.com 469-299-0018

Having overall 8 years of Software industry experience as Software Quality Engineer. Focus has been in Test Automation, Functional Testing, Rest API Testing and Mobile Native App Testing in AGILE environment.

- Strong Experience with Agile methodology, Waterfall and Software Development life cycle(SDLC).
- Extensive experience on automation framework development using Selenium Web Driver, Java, TestNG, Maven and other open source tools.
- Developed Page Object Model (POM) and Hybrid automation frameworks using Selenium WebDriver \TestNG
- Experience in Web Services REST APIs testing using SOAPUI and REST API libraries.
- Jenkins CI\CD continuous integration development for automation tests for quick releases.
- Created Jenkin Jobs for nightly runs for automation suites and triage failures and fix.
- Project estimation, Test Strategy, Test Plan, Test Metrics and Report dashboard.
- Experience in distributed test automation execution using Selenium Grid and Jenkins.
- Participated in formal test case reviews with the technical and business team.
- Strong experience in ETL and Database testing, wrote complex SQL queries for Data Profiling, Data validation, Source-2-Target Mapping and BI Report Testing.
- · Excellent skill in finding bugs and defect management tools HP ALM, Jira, Rally.
- Mobile Native app testing on Android platform IOS.
- Strong Knowledge in Git hub, Perforce and SVN.
- Hands on experience in Agile Tool Rally and Jira.
- Extensive experience with Onshore/Offshore model.
- Strong analytical, trouble-shooting, works under pressure and problem-solving skills.
- Experience with various types of testing like System testing, functional testing, Regression testing, Integration testing and REST API testing.
- Experience collaborating across ecosystems and across functional areas.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

# Work Experience

## **QA Test Engineer**

HSBC - McLean, VA September 2017 to Present

#### Responsibilities:

- Analyzed and understood functional requirements from business requirement specifications and identify the test scenarios.
- Involved in preparing a detailed test plan by thoroughly reviewing SRS documents, system design and technical design documents.

- Created manual Test Cases in HP QC/HP ALM for various User Stories based on Release and Sprint Plan.
- Extensively used Quality Center for test planning, maintaining both manual test cases and automation test scripts, test execution, reporting and tracking defects.
- Performed web applications, mobile testing on iOS, android operating systems.
- Defect tracking using Version One Tool.
- Experience in using Defect management systems such as HP ALM (Quality Center).
- Install and Uninstallation testing for the builds and patches in various OS and environments.
- Worked on both real devices and simulators for testing.
- Involved in assigning daily task to the offshore team.
- Performed the tasks of assisting agile tester in conducting test plans and test cases
- Worked with the business users on User Acceptance Testing by mentoring them on various aspects of testing. Understood the Business Logic, User Requirements and test-objectives to develop Use Case Scenarios, Test plans, Test cases.
- Acted as the liaison between the business and technical teams.
- Proactively addressed potential issues that may affect the system and worked with developers to resolve the matter.

Environment: Selenium, Oracle9i, Java, MS Excel, MS Project, MS PowerPoint, UNIX, Oracle PL/SQL, UML, Rational Rose, Requisite Pro, Clear Case, Rational Clear Quest 2002, MS Office suite, MS Visio

# **QA Test Engineer**

Freddie Mac, VA April 2016 to September 2017

#### Responsibilities

- Writing test plans, test cases, defect reports and test completion reports where systems under test were thick client, multi-tier web applications, mainframe and mobile devices.
- Supporting the offshore testing team by answering questions, reviewing test plans, test cases and test scenarios.
- Experience in Selenium Testing tools (Web Driver and RC) and CodedUI tool.
- Experience in Design and Development of test automation frameworks for web application using Selenium and CodedUI testing tool.
- Implemented simulator for Mobile App Testing in Android and IOS Platform using Appium.
- Executing the test plans on web and mobile (Apple & Android) as per requirements.
- Experience in load and performance testing tool [Meter.
- Used HP ALM to analyze, track and report defects. Worked on uploading all the Test cases to the Quality Center for the current and prior releases.
- Performed Defect Root Cause Analysis, interacted with related Team, and tracked defects in a HP ALM.
- Test REST Web Services APIs with open source tools and Ruby framework in Linux environment.
- Used Jenkins as continuous integration server to run automated test suites.
- Uploading test cases, executing tests and entering defects within HP ALM Quality Center.
- Acquiring and organizing large amounts of data for testing.
- Testing the Web API for functional validation through VS and Soap API tool.
- Worked with source version control tool such as Subversion (SVN).
- Performed End to End Mobile Testing on Android using Appium.
- Involved in acceptance testing using Cucumber. Used firebug and Firepath to access webpage script variables.

- Validated failed automation test cases as defects or false hits.
- Communicating effectively in a project team environment while leading defect triage calls to establish defect priorities, severity, commenting on the projects inputs and assigning defects to the responsible party for the next steps.
- Reporting during project team meetings to give status updates, testing progress, issues and escalation points.

Environment: Selenium (WebDriver), Java, QTP, SQL, WebDriver, Quality Centre ALM, HTML, Restful, SQL, JIRA, TestNG, Appium, SOAP, VB Script.

## **QA Tester**

Tek Sources, OH

November 2014 to December 2015

### Responsibilities:

- Automated the Manual test cases of the application.
- Reviewed the Business requirement documents and the Technical Specification.
- Practiced Agile methodology by managing requirements, controlling software changes and followed iterative approach through the software development.
- Prepared Requirement Traceability Matrix to verify that all stated and derived requirements are allocated to system components.
- Reviewed test cases in the automation perspective to identify reusable actions, functions using Quality Centre.
- Responsible for designing test conditions, test plan, test cases, execution and entering defects for web and mobile applications
- Developed optimized QTP scripts for regression testing with various data sources, environment variables, and config files to enhance the QTP test scripts with VB scripts and developed user-defined functions for frequent reuse.
- Developed QTP Scripts and executed them for test data set up required to conduct Functional testing
- Collaborated with the Release Deployment team to create and maintain an automated nightly build verification (smoke) test as well as Operations and Production Support team to develop reusable automated scripts for Database Updates and basic regression testing.
- Converting previously automated QTP application in Selenium with Junit and xPath.

Environment: Quick Test Pro (QTP), Quality Centre, Selenium, Core Java, Java Script, Oracle, HTML, Office, MS Project, Ms FrontPage.

## **Senior Software Test Engineer**

Wipro

November 2010 to January 2013

#### Responsibilities:

- Writing test plans, test cases, defect reports and test completion reports where systems under test were thick client, multi-tier web applications, mainframe and mobile devices.
- Supporting the offshore testing team by answering questions, reviewing test plans, test cases and test scenarios.
- Experience in Selenium Testing tools (Web Driver and RC) and CodedUI tool.
- Experience in Design and Development of test automation frameworks for web application using Selenium and CodedUI testing tool.
- Executing the test plans on web and mobile (Apple & Android) as per requirements.

- Experienced in load and performance testing tool JMeter.
- Used HP ALM to analyze, track and report defects. Worked on uploading all the Test cases to the Quality Center for the current and prior releases.
- Performed Defect Root Cause Analysis, interacted with related Team, and tracked defects in a HP
- Test REST Web Services APIs with open source tools and Ruby framework in Linux environment.
- Used Jenkins as continuous integration server to run automated test suites.
- Uploading test cases, executing tests and entering defects within HP ALM Quality Center.
- Acquiring and organizing large amounts of data for testing.
- Testing the Web API for functional validation through VS and Soap API tool.
- Worked with source version control tool such as Subversion (SVN).
- Validated failed automation test cases as defects or false hits.
- Communicating effectively in a project team environment while leading defect triage calls to establish defect priorities, severity, commenting on the projects inputs and assigning defects to the responsible party for the next steps.
- Reporting during project team meetings to give status updates, testing progress, issues and escalation points.

Environment: SQL Server 2005, Selenium WebDriver, UML, HP Quality Center 11.0, Visual Studio 2005, Visual Source Safe, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft VISIO

# **Software Engineer**

Wipro

December 2009 to November 2010

#### Description:

The purpose of MyAsset project is to develop a web based portal to make end users and managers aware of IT assets they hold and bring in visibility on costs associated. Features such as Improvisation in end user usability and experience, automated email notification, modifications in Enterprise Level.

#### Responsibilities:

- Documented the Current Business process to help understand and analyze the future requirements.
- Assisted the Senior Business Analyst in writing Functional Requirement Specifications (FRS) and User Requirements Specification (URS).
- Gathered business requirements through interviews, surveys, prototyping and observation from Portfolio Managers and UI (User Interface).
- Created Use Case Diagrams and Data Flow Diagrams in MS Visio to determine the data flow via various systems.
- Helped the business team in setting up UAT environment.
- Review of Unit Test Cases and performed data accuracy, data validation, and data integrity testing by querying the database using SQL Queries to check for data stability on the Server.
- Managed the System Test Execution phase and Participated in the daily defect meetings during System Testing with the Development Lead and UAT Test Manager.
- Used HP Quality center for requirements, test plan and defect Management.
- Performed manual front-end testing to check all functionalities of different modules.
- Facilitated the weekly meetings with the review teams to continuously improve the QA process for the application development.
- Contribution on the Release Note, Test Case Report, Bidirectional Traceability Matrix and System Test Closure Report.

• Used Visual SourceSafe (VSS) for version control of the source code along with the maintenance of the builds and the relevant documents of the same.

Environment: SQL Server 2005, TOAD, HP Quality Center 11.0, C#, Microsoft Excel, ERWIN Data Modeler, Visual Studio 2005

# **Software Engineer**

Mahindra Satyam November 2007 to December 2009

#### Description:

Insurance Management Application is a Web-based application for a typical Life Insurance company. The goal of the Project is to identify successful sales and promotional channels by region, product offering, and service, identify renewable policies and revenue potential and analyze customers behavior pattern over specific time period to fine tune products and services to better meet customer needs.

## Responsibilities:

- Requirement Analysis and Contributed on Design document for the assigned modules.
- Involved in the Code cleanup activity, coding and deploying the application.
- · Actively involved in the database design and table creation using SQL Server 2005.
- Handled Change Requests and Code Merging related activities.
- Captured and tested all modifications to proposed functional requirements.
- Designated as Single Point of Contact (SPOC) for the users with regards to business needs, changes and enhancements in the application.
- Participated in UAT and follow-ups with testing and development teams for defect resolutions.
- Fixed development issues in the testing phase.
- Worked closely with the UI team to ensure that the product has consistent look and feel over the entire application platforms.

Environment: Visual Studio 2005, SQL Server 2000/2005, C#.Net, ERWIN Data Modeler, Microsoft Excel, TOAD, Windows 2003 Server, Visual Source Safe

## Education

#### Bachelor's

## Skills

TESTING, SQL, MS SQL SERVER, SQL SERVER, VERSION CONTROL

# Additional Information

#### **SOFTWARE Skills:**

Methodologies Waterfall, Agile/Scrum

Testing Tools Selenium WebDriver, TestNG, Selenium Grid, Cucumber, Jmeter, SoapUI, QTP, Appium, Eclipse

Build & Integration Tools Maven, Jenkins
Version Control tool GitHub, SVN
Programming Languages HTML5, JAVA\J2EE, C, C++, Shell script, C#
Databases MySQL, Oracle11g, SQL Server, PL/SQL
Defect Management Tools HP ALM, JIRA, RALLY,